After Gallipoli there was still a war to be won.
Beneath Hill 60 is a drama, history, war film directed by Jeremy Sims.
The true story of Australia's cat-and-mouse underground mine warfare—one of the
most misunderstood, misrepresented and mystifying conflicts of WW I.
It was secret struggle BENEATH the Western Front that combined
daring engineering, technology and science.
Few on the surface knew of the brave, claustrophobic and
sometimes barbaric work of these tunnellers.
Captain Oliver Woodward, played by Brendan Cowell.
Frank Tiffin, played by Harrison Gilbertson.
Sergeant Bill Fraser, played by Steve Le Marquand.
Norman Morris, played by Gyton Grantley.
Jim Sneddon, played by Alan Dukes.
Walter Sneddon, played by Alex Thompson.
Beneath Hill 60 is a 2010 Australian war film directed by Jeremy Sims
(credited as Jeremy Hartley Sims) and written by David Roach.
Based on the 2011 upcoming book Beneath Hill 60: The Extraordinary True Story of the Secret
War Being Waged Beneath the Trenches of the Western Front by Will Davies.
Set during World War I, the film tells the story of the 1st Australian Tunnelling Company's
efforts in mining underneath Hill 60 in the Ypres Salient on the Western Front.
During the war, a series of mines filled with explosive charges were placed
beneath German lines to aid the advance of British troops.
The screenplay is based on an account of the ordeal written by Captain
Oliver Woodward, who is portrayed by Brendan Cowell in the film.
Beneath Hill 60 was released in Australia on 15 April 2010.
In July 2009, it was reported that there were plans to have the film showcased at the 2010 Cannes Film Festival but,
ultimately, it was not included in the official competition or any other section in the festival.
The film explores themes of world war i, western front, trench warfare.
The tone is emotional.